<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Big Picture</title>
<description>News Stories in Photographs from the Boston Globe.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014</copyright>
<generator>Methode</generator>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Holi Celebrations 2015</title>http:<description>Holi is a festival that marks events in Hindu mythology and provides photographers with a colorful visual feast. It celebrates the beginning of spring, and falls on the last full moon day of the lunar month Phalguna, which was on March 6 this year. It is a joyous ritual when intense colors, light, emotion, and energy combine in a surreal vision of spirituality.
 -- 
By Leanne Burden Seidel&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/03/06/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/2015-03-06T144601Z_609062234_GM1EB361QZV01_RTRMADP_3_INDIA-RELIGION.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Widows daubed in colors danced as they took part in the Holi celebrations organized by nongovernmental organization Sulabh International in the northern Indian state of Uttar Pradesh on March 6. Traditionally in Hindu culture, widows are expected to renounce earthly pleasure so they do not celebrate Holi. But widows at the shelter, who have been abandoned by their families, celebrated the festival by throwing flowers and colored powder.
  (Adnan Abidi/Reuters)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/03/06/holi-celebrations/NscLFB5N5LJ9w1F56rnMBO/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/03/06/holi-celebrations/NscLFB5N5LJ9w1F56rnMBO/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 20:40:27 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Globe photos of the month, February 2015</title>http:<description>

&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/02/25/BostonGlobe.com/Arts/Images/Tlumacki_snow-relatedwildlifeinuries_arts058.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;A screech owl was treated at the New England Wildlife Center in Weymouth for a wing fractured in Abington during a snowstorm. 
  (John Tlumacki/Globe Staff)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/03/04/globe-photos-month-february/tuVHJywIxMfgf4qGssgBeI/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/03/04/globe-photos-month-february/tuVHJywIxMfgf4qGssgBeI/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 15:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Documenting one family’s home birth experience</title>http:<description>Home births aren’t for everyone. But for Ashley Bennett, having her second child at home in Medford was an opportunity to be encouraged and supported at a time when she, and many women, feel at their most vulnerable. The birth plan gave Ashleyand her husband, Mike, an array of delivery options, but, as always when it comes to birth, circumstances were unpredictable. The night Ashley went into labor, their toddler, Marin, came down with a fever. And Ashley’s dreams of a water birth — in a giant portable tub — dried up when the new addition to the family, Isaac Douglas Bennett, arrived before the tub was filled. Besides doula Catherine McKeown-Lindsey and midwives Tara Kenny and Audra Karp, the Bennetts allowed Globe photographer Jessica Rinaldi to witness the family’s private moments.
&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/02/02/BostonGlobe.com/Lifestyle/Images/homebirth01.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;At her four-month checkup, Ashley Bennett's 2-year-old daughter, Marin, leaned over to give her a kiss as she lays on the couch at her midwife's home in Cambridge. When Ashley first became pregnant with Marin, she made calls to both a hospital and a home birth midwife to see about setting up a prenatal appointment.  While the ObGyn's office was informal telling her when and where she would deliver, the midwife first asked how she was feeling.  "The idea that someone who didn't know me cared how I was feeling and doing as a person may seem trivial, but it was such a stark contrast to my first prenatal call at the hospital that I was instantly touched by her intentional care for me," Ashley said.  "As much as I read with our first baby on birth, that initial call spoke volumes and solidified this path for me.  I cancelled my prenatal at the hospital and I never looked back."
  (Jessica Rinaldi/Globe Staff)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/03/01/family-welcomes-baby-boy-birthed-home/zD4EFANnHvbYBSrkPSaKSK/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/03/01/family-welcomes-baby-boy-birthed-home/zD4EFANnHvbYBSrkPSaKSK/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 22:01:20 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Roll out the barrels</title>http:<description>Saudi Arabia’s oil exports have risen in February in response to stronger demand from customers. As OPEC’s top producer battles for market share Reuters photographers around the globe have been photographing oil barrels to document how they are utilized once the fuel has been used.
 -- 
By Reuters&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/02/27/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/2015-02-20T100244Z_1892435390_LM2EB2K0J1401_RTRMADP_3_SAUDI-OIL-EXPORTS.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Men stack oil barrels at a depot in Santo Domingo, Feb. 6, 2015. A group of resident Haitians sell the metal barrels for $9 each to be used as garbage bins, or made into grills or to store water. 
  (Ricardo Rojas/Reuters)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/27/roll-out-barrels/GUX3QkulFmKluPQkTMm46K/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/27/roll-out-barrels/GUX3QkulFmKluPQkTMm46K/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 23:32:36 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Chinese New Year 2015</title>http:<description>The Chinese Lunar New Year began Feb. 19 ushering in the Year of the Sheep, according to the Chinese zodiac. The new year also marks the beginning of the Spring Festival in China, which continues until the Lantern Festival on the 15th day. 
 -- 
By Lloyd Young&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/02/19/BostonGlobe.com/Foreign/Images/463841842.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Chinese artists perform a dragon dance at a local amusement park during celebrations for the Lunar New Year on Feb. 19 in Beijing, China.The Chinese Lunar New Year of the Sheep also known as the Spring Festival, which is based on the Lunisolar Chinese calendar, is celebrated from the first day of the first month of the lunar year and ends with Lantern Festival on the Fifteenth day. 


  (Kevin Frayer/Getty Images)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/25/chinese-new-year/CgqhSSPiMb2LscxZnhiwpI/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/25/chinese-new-year/CgqhSSPiMb2LscxZnhiwpI/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 22:05:48 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Wintry woes for the MBTA</title>http:<description>The MBTA has been struggling to restore service after a massive amount of snow fell on the state, beginning with the blizzard in late January. Beverly Scott, MBTA general manager, said “tremendous progress” had been made in an “absolutely unbelievable recovery” effort. She also said that the commuter rail system is “still having challenges,” operating at a little over 60 percent. Scott said the MBTA woes this winter had sounded several “wakeup calls,” and that the system needs more investment. A look back at our recent public transit woes, due to an unusually harsh winter. 
 -- 
By Bill Greene&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/02/09/BostonGlobe.com/National/Images/ryan_snowagain14_met.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Earlier in February, a snow-covered third rail caused a T train in Quincy to get stuck. Passengers had to be evacuated by the Quincy Fire Department. 
  (David L. Ryan/Globe Staff)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/23/wintry-woes-for-mbta/UFasXMvGjJnzmfYTF2WMAI/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/23/wintry-woes-for-mbta/UFasXMvGjJnzmfYTF2WMAI/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 19:05:45 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Carnival and Mardi Gras 2015</title>http:<description>Pre-Lenten celebrations around the globe, including Carnival and Mardi Gras, wrapped up earlier this week before the marking of Ash Wednesday. Historians say the tradition dates back to Roman times, when the newly converted Christians retained vestiges of their pagan festival, “Lupercalia,” as a period of celebration before the penance during the 40 days of Lent.
 -- 
By Lloyd Young&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/02/20/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/04623472.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;The Queen of Panama City carnival Onissis Samaniego participates during a parade of the Panama City carnival in Panama City, Panama, on Feb. 16. 
  (Alejandro Bolivar/EPA)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/20/carnival-and-mardi-gras/c51BqtnakLzeQKiZVt3fTM/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/20/carnival-and-mardi-gras/c51BqtnakLzeQKiZVt3fTM/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 23:47:53 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Westminster Kennel Club Dog Show</title>http:<description>The Westminster Kennel Club 139th Annual Dog show took place this week, filling Manhattan with thousands of competitors, including 192 different canine breeds. Owners and dogs traveled from around the world to participate in this iconic event.
 -- 
By Leanne Burden Seidel&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/02/18/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/0c155d32962d4d198fe0def8c20f44f9-0c155d32962d4d198fe0def8c20f44f9-0.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Jim Grieco, a cameraman for the USA Network, films Bloodhound Nathan in the benching area of the Westminster Kennel Club dog show, Feb. 16, at Madison Square Garden in New York. 
  (Mary Altaffer/Associated Press)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/18/westminster-kennel-club-dog-show/YzrtgeE7LcunKGhdCE9GtK/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/18/westminster-kennel-club-dog-show/YzrtgeE7LcunKGhdCE9GtK/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 01:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Fire and Ice</title>http:<description>In Japan, winter festivals in the past week make for interesting visual juxtapositions. Snow and Ice festivals display large illuminated sculptures for the public to enjoy. In Shingu, the end of winter is celebrated by thousand of men lighting torches on a mountain shrine.
 -- 
By Leanne Burden Seidel&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/02/13/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/462845024.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Japanese men wear Fundoshi, a traditional Japanese undergarment and pray during the purifying body wash ceremony ahead of attending the Oto fire festival. The male-only festival celebrates the close of winter and sees nearly 2000 men run down the 538 steep stone steps from the mountain shrine. The day begins at dusk with Noboriko preparing themselves by bathing in saltwater during a purifying ceremony on a beach in Oiigahama.
  (Chris McGrath/Getty Images)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/15/fire-and-ice/IJoQ0RIgfsrCiyqi25tijP/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/15/fire-and-ice/IJoQ0RIgfsrCiyqi25tijP/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 21:18:21 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Snow keeps piling up in New England</title>http:<description>The record-breaking snow amounts just keep piling up since the blizzard that hit the Northeast in late January, causing major commuting issues, damage to property, and sore backs across the region.
 -- 
By Lloyd Young&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/02/11/BostonGlobe.com/Metro/Images/ryan_redlinebus3_met.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;A long line formed  in North Quincy Wednesday morning with commuters waiting for some 2 hours to take a shuttle bus to the JFK Red Line station. 

  (David L. Ryan/Globe Staff)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/11/snow-keeps-piling-new-england/YttQKdnPFScuG6m4ZeRE8I/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/11/snow-keeps-piling-new-england/YttQKdnPFScuG6m4ZeRE8I/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 21:10:09 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Portraits of conflict in Ukraine</title>http:<description>The heavy fighting in Ukraine has returned this past month, with leaders around the world hoping for a diplomatic solution to the crisis. Photographers have captured the lives of the soldiers on both sides and the civilians living among the destruction and bloodshed. 
 -- 
By Leanne Burden Seidel&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/02/09/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/2015-02-06T164208Z_179506529_GM1EB2700ZF01_RTRMADP_3_UKRAINE-CRISIS-CONVOYS.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;A woman cries as she waits for humanitarian aid near a Ukrainian serviceman stands nearby in Debaltseve, eastern Ukraine, Feb. 6. Convoys of buses converged from two sides on the town of Debaltseve in eastern Ukraine after separatist rebels and government forces appeared to have patched together a truce to allow civilians to be evacuated. 
  (Gleb Garanich/Reuters)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/09/portraits-conflict-ukraine/M1GPfEURBa5nya11JgnWBN/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/09/portraits-conflict-ukraine/M1GPfEURBa5nya11JgnWBN/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 22:56:58 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Globe photos of the month, January 2015</title>http:<description>Here’s a look at just some of the best images taken by Globe photographers last month including the coverage of winter storms, a new governor taking office and the Patriots playoff run to the Super Bowl.
 -- 
By Lloyd Young&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/01/28/BostonGlobe.com/Metro/Images/28blizzardmainpic105.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Noah Bicchieri, 29, and his dog, Caruso, walked through deep snow between houses on Plum Island.

  (Jessica Rinaldi/Globe Staff)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/06/globe-photos-month-january/VXjSkJ3viKVspL10TfovCI/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/06/globe-photos-month-january/VXjSkJ3viKVspL10TfovCI/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 02:50:45 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Super Bowl victory parade for the New England Patriots</title>http:<description>

&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/02/04/BostonGlobe.com/Metro/Images/Tlumacki_newenglandpatriotduckboatparade_metro298.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Thousands of fans lined the parade route on the snow-covered sidewalks of Boylston Street to watch the New England Patriots celebrate their Super Bowl win.
  (John Tlumacki/Globe Staff)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/04/super-bowl-victory-parade-for-new-england-patriots/tJgP6oi90X4VpWSKuCtrhK/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/04/super-bowl-victory-parade-for-new-england-patriots/tJgP6oi90X4VpWSKuCtrhK/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 16:42:17 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Super Bowl XLIX: Patriots defeat Seahawks</title>http:<description>The Patriots defeated the Seahawks, 28-24, in Super Bowl XLIX to claim their fourth NFL championship. Tom Brady was the gamne’s MVP.
&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/02/02/BostonGlobe.com/ReceivedContent/Images/bradbelichicktropht.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Tom Brady and Bill Belichick teamed up to win their fourth Lombardi Trophy.
  (Barry Chin/Globe Staff)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/01/super-bowl-xlix-patriots-seahawks/JjuFryOOxnsOfWxd2VIFVI/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/02/01/super-bowl-xlix-patriots-seahawks/JjuFryOOxnsOfWxd2VIFVI/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 06:17:16 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Road to K-pop stardom</title>http:<description>Thousands of Korean children dream of becoming household names like rapper Psy, whose 2012 “Gangnam Style” video was a global YouTube hit, often putting up with punishing schedules in the hope of one day making it big in the music industry. A recent survey of pre-teens showed that 21 percent of respondents wanted to be K-pop (Korean pop) stars when they grow up, the most popular career choice.
 -- 
By Reuters&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/01/30/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/2015-01-22T082623Z_1818973589_GM1EB1M0MGD01_RTRMADP_3_KOREA-KPOP-WIDERIMAGE.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Members of South Korean girl group GFriend watch a recording of their stage performance during a dress rehearsal for "The Show" in Seoul, Jan. 20. 
  (Kim Hong-Ji/Reuters)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/30/road-pop-stardom/qmsTVMsOtI5FEyYZfzJ5yM/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/30/road-pop-stardom/qmsTVMsOtI5FEyYZfzJ5yM/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:54:50 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Massive snowstorm hits Northeast</title>http:<description>The blizzard of 2015 blasted the region with wind-whipped snow that piled nearly 3-feet high in some places.
&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/01/28/BostonGlobe.com/ReceivedContent/Images/storm77.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Piles of snow along the streets of Squantum frame the City of Boston across Dorchester Bay.
  (Stan Grossfeld/Globe Staff)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/27/massive-snowstorm-hits-northeast/Wc4dHUyw3eo8PvXfdF1sWJ/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/27/massive-snowstorm-hits-northeast/Wc4dHUyw3eo8PvXfdF1sWJ/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:32:17 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Unrest in Yemen</title>http:<description>The future for Yemen is uncertain after the president resigned this week after a Houthi rebel takeover of the country. Thousands demonstrated on Friday as lawmakers wait to convene over the  weekend.
 -- 
By Leanne Burden Seidel&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/01/23/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/2015-01-23T152641Z_1608995879_GF2EB1N16EM01_RTRMADP_3_YEMEN-SECURITY.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Army and police officers loyal to the Houthi movement shout slogans as they take part in a demonstration to show support to the movement in Sanaa Jan. 23. Yemen drifted deeper into political limbo on Friday after President Abd-Rabbu Mansour Hadi resigned in exasperation at a Houthi rebel takeover of the country, a move that appeared to catch the Iran-backed group off balance. 
  (Khaled Abdullah/Reuters)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/23/unrest-yemen/Le6pjXTp5j2dEScy4EQ5tK/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/23/unrest-yemen/Le6pjXTp5j2dEScy4EQ5tK/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 01:07:18 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Declining water levels in the Dead Sea</title>http:<description>Originally one of the world’s first health resorts, the Dead Sea in Israel has a far from healthy future as its water levels continue to decline. In fact, it has been estimated that since the 1950s the water levels have dropped about 130 feet. The dangerously low level has been attributed to an imbalance between the amount of incoming and outgoing water. Known also as the Sea of Salt, separating Israel to the west and Jordan to the east, the lake’s surface and shores are 1407 feet below the level making it earth’s lowest elevation on land. The problem of the annual declining rate is due largely to the reduction of inflowing of water from the Jordan River. This has been attributed to the increased current consumption of water within the Jordan River water and irrigation drainage basin. Water resources in the region are scarce and affect Israel, the West Bank, Lebanon, Syria and Jordan that are located within and bordering the basin. The sea is called ‘dead’ because its high salinity prevents aquatic organisms such as fish and aquatic plants from living in it. 
 -- 
By European Pressphoto Agency&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/01/21/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/04547216.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;An abandoned tourist Boat shipwreck lying at the Dead Sea coastal resort near Ein Gedi, Israel. According to media reports, the Dead Sea water level is dropping with an average of 3 feet per year since the first water level measurements in 1927.


  (Abir Sultan/EPA)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/21/declining-water-levels-dead-sea/trojg9QUNZSRLeZzBD765M/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/21/declining-water-levels-dead-sea/trojg9QUNZSRLeZzBD765M/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 04:39:16 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Bird’s Eye View</title>http:<description>A change in perspective can make everything look a little different.  Patterns emerge, shapes coalesce, and chaos simplifies.  
&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/01/19/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/Lane/Copy%20of%202014-09-30T042232Z_2055143147_GM1EA9U0Y8C01_RTRMADP_3_PERU-ENVIRONMENT.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Aerial view of a river in Peru's Amazon region of Loreto, September 29, 2014. 
  (ENRIQUE CASTRO-MENDIVIL/REUTERS)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/19/bird-eye-view/N1jkLwu4rauBzDmDAS3DcJ/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/19/bird-eye-view/N1jkLwu4rauBzDmDAS3DcJ/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 23:57:16 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>The Naga tribes of Myanmar</title>http:<description> In Myanmar, around 120,000 people live in the Naga Self-Administered Zone in Sagaing Division where they survive mainly by subsistence farming and hunting. Cultural practices are changing - for example, younger men now wear trousers rather than traditional loincloths - although many Naga communities remain impoverished and inaccessible by road. The Naga speak dozens of languages and many of those in Myanmar use Burmese as a lingua franca.
&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/01/16/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/2015-01-09T114241Z_794700424_LM2EB1813YO01_RTRMADP_3_MYANMAR-NAGA-WIDERIMAGE.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;A man who claims to be 100 years old wears a hat adorned with wild boar tusks in Donhe township in the Naga Self-Administered Zone in northwest Myanmar Dec. 30. Naga men traditionally wore animal parts such as tusks and tiger teeth, although the practice is less common now and younger men usually do so only for festivals.
  (Soe Zeya Tun/Reuters)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/16/the-naga-tribes-myanmar/2vat0F9BMYfQs3VbHFPWHO/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/16/the-naga-tribes-myanmar/2vat0F9BMYfQs3VbHFPWHO/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 23:23:14 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Dakar Rally 2015</title>http:<description> The 13-stage Dakar Rally is traveling through Argentina, Chile, and Bolivia via motorcycle, quad bike, car, or truck over extreme terrain. Competitors and support crews come from around the world to challenge their mechanical, driving, and orienteering skills. The race wraps up this Saturday in Buenos Aires after covering the more than 5,592-mile loop-shaped course.
 -- 
By Lloyd Young&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/01/13/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/2015-01-13T153448Z_661137115_GM1EB1D0FX201_RTRMADP_3_RALLYING-DAKAR-1021.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;KTM rider Boldbaatar Damdinkhorloo of Mongolia rides during the eighth stage of the Dakar Rally 2015 on the Salar de Uyuni salt flat, from Uyuni to Iquique on Jan. 12.


  (Jean-Paul Pelissier/Reuters)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/14/dakar-rally/IyTvSZIqZY8fu0AAa3s4eO/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/14/dakar-rally/IyTvSZIqZY8fu0AAa3s4eO/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 20:58:20 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Unity Rallies for France terror victims</title>http:<description>A crowd estimated to be between one to three million people marched in Paris to remember the victims of a series of terror attacks which claimed the lives of 17 people.  The Paris march was said to rival crowds that turned out for the liberation of France after WWII.  Other rallies throughout France drew massive crowds as well.  
 -- 
By Lane Turner&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/01/11/BostonGlobe.com/National/Images/2015-01-11T173738Z_347305065_LR2EB1B1CYFBJ_RTRMADP_3_FRANCE-SHOOTING.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;A man holds a giant pencil as he takes part in a solidarity march in the streets of Paris January 11, 2015. 
  (STEPHANE MAHE)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/12/unity-rallies-for-france-terror-victims/YyFyYsLlVoe4G8B2B4wbRP/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/12/unity-rallies-for-france-terror-victims/YyFyYsLlVoe4G8B2B4wbRP/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 14:13:04 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>The Natural World: Animal patterns</title>http:<description>Animals offer photographers a wealth of visual material. Interesting forms, texture, patterns, movement, and color enrich the image. This is a selection of recent photos of animals and their environment from around the world that are captured with this in mind.
 -- 
By Leanne Burden Seidel&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/01/08/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/2015-01-05T124906Z_411652553_GM1EB151LM801_RTRMADP_3_BRITAIN-ANIMALS.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Sumatran tiger cubs and their parents walk around their enclosure at London Zoo in London, Jan. 5, 2015. The annual stock take and animal count, a requirement of London Zoo's license, included additions to the international conservation breeding programme such as the three tiger cubs and Philippine crocodiles. 
  (Toby Melville /Reuters)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/09/the-natural-world-animal-patterns/06v2GyS9HJ7OeKsos0DHoK/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/09/the-natural-world-animal-patterns/06v2GyS9HJ7OeKsos0DHoK/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 22:48:09 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Charlie Baker Inauguration</title>http:<description>Charles Duane Baker Jr., a Beacon Hill budget whiz turned health insurance chief executive and politician, was sworn in Thursday as the 72d governor of Massachusetts.
&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/01/08/BostonGlobe.com/Metro/Images/ryan_bakerinaugural5_met.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Charlie Baker “fist-bumped” on the front steps before the inaugural celebration.
  (David L. Ryan/globe staff)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/08/charlie-baker-inauguration/mftwdg3Qg8Tam584Sw6YtK/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/08/charlie-baker-inauguration/mftwdg3Qg8Tam584Sw6YtK/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 02:59:42 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Paris attack</title>http:<description>Authorities are looking for the armed gunmen who stormed the office of the weekly satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo in Paris and killed 12 people including the editor and two police officers. The paper had a history of publishing cartoons deemed offensive to Muslims.
&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2015/01/07/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/2015-01-07T185533Z_754191836_GM1EB1807Z701_RTRMADP_3_FRANCE-SHOOTING.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;People try to light candles to form the word "Charlie" to pay tribute to the victims of a shooting by gunmen at the offices of weekly satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo in Paris, in front of the European Parliament in Brussels on Jan. 7. Gunmen stormed the Paris offices of the weekly satirical newspaper Charlie Hebdo, renowned for lampooning radical Islam, killing at least 12 people, including two police officers in the worst militant attack on French soil in recent decades. 

  (Francois Lenoir/Reuters)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/07/paris-attack/uBmT4MiTPlmjL0fPyrSDEJ/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/07/paris-attack/uBmT4MiTPlmjL0fPyrSDEJ/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 21:46:40 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Globe photos of the month, December 2014</title>http:<description>

&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/12/11/BostonGlobe.com/Metro/Images/ryan_diein1_met-7878.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt; Medical students wearing white coats held a “die-in” at Harvard Medical School’s Medical Education Center in Boston on International Human Rights Day. Demonstrations were also held at medical schools in New York, St. Louis, Philadelphia, Cleveland, Chicago, Los Angeles, San Francisco, Washington, D.C., and elsewhere to protest the lack of indictments for police killings and to spotlight racial bias as a public health issue .


  (David L. Ryan/Globe Staff)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/02/globe-photos-month-december/IZ6dhELQdhKYrIGUlqLv6K/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2015/01/02/globe-photos-month-december/IZ6dhELQdhKYrIGUlqLv6K/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 17:27:09 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Daily Life: December 2014</title>http:<description>For this edition of our look at daily life we share images from France, China, Cuba, Pakistan, United States and other countries from around the world.
 -- 
By Lloyd Young&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/12/30/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/4bc0a644e68d4740a22f130c3f2f0bcd-58314da568694400b79df6a99621ddff-0.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;A man portraying Santa Claus moves between cars while greeting passengers during a Polar Express holiday train ride to the "North Pole" on the Maine Narrow Gauge Railroad on Dec. 19 in Portland. The Polar Express is the largest annual fundraiser for the railroad's museum.


  (Robert F. Bukaty/Associated Press)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/31/daily-life-december/QZ4H8xkcERm8IGieJXza1I/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/31/daily-life-december/QZ4H8xkcERm8IGieJXza1I/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 14:21:29 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Seasonal lights</title>http:<description>Around the world, nights look brighter this time of year. Illuminations of all kinds help celebrate holidays or festivities.
 -- 
By Leanne Burden Seidel&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/12/18/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/Leanne-light%20displays/1fbde77ed9a84aab814c593be6bd101c-1fbde77ed9a84aab814c593be6bd101c-0.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;People enjoy an annual yearend illumination in Shiodome district in Tokyo, Japan, Nov. 24. 
  (Shuji Kajiyama/Associated Press)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/24/seasonal-lights/1YH1pC4GyDHum8Cncfjy0M/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/24/seasonal-lights/1YH1pC4GyDHum8Cncfjy0M/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2014 14:26:56 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Hands in the news</title>http:<description>Hands tell stories. They are are functional and they have the power to communicate emotion. This post is edited from today’s wire photos. The hands in these photographs represent hope, communication, power, connection and longing. 
 -- 
By Thea Breite&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/12/22/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/tb_hands/e773c519b70247688d8d1b8fc52bdf71-74f311453f11486a830b91a3baf6a26a-0.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;An Indian girl participates in a street play to create awareness on violence against women during a protest ahead of the second anniversary of the deadly gang rape of a 23-year-old physiotherapy student on a bus, in New Delhi, India. The case sparked public outrage and helped make women's safety a common topic of conversation in a country where rape is often viewed as a woman's personal shame to bear.
  (Tsering Topgyal/AP)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/22/hands-news/B2xAn0M80CpTzFpD2xX18I/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/22/hands-news/B2xAn0M80CpTzFpD2xX18I/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 20:29:50 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>2014 Year in Pictures: Part III</title>http:<description>Photos from the last four months of the 2014 depicting news events and daily life around the world.
&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/12/08/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/YEARENDER-%20Leanne/TS-Par7993150.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;A woman reacts after her husband is suspected of dying from the Ebola virus, in the Liberian capital Monrovia, on Oct. 4. By far the most deadly epidemic of Ebola on record has spread into five west African countries since the start of the year, infecting more than 7,000 people and killing about half of them. 
  (Pascal Guyot/AFP/Getty Images)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/19/year-pictures-part-iii/iyG4PgzuA8sy4utXrSfGxJ/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/19/year-pictures-part-iii/iyG4PgzuA8sy4utXrSfGxJ/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 21:19:34 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>2014 Year in Pictures: Part II</title>http:<description>Photographs from May-August on a range topics from around the world.
 -- 
By Lloyd Young&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/12/16/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/03c3c1dd49d04e3f85c2a3909d8e0002-03c3c1dd49d04e3f85c2a3909d8e0002-0.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;A protester takes shelter from smoke billowing around during protests on Aug. 13 against the shooting of black teenager Michael Brown in Freguson, Mo., by white police officer Darren Wilson. 


  (David Carson/St. Louis Post-Dispatch via Associated Press)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/17/year-pictures-part/cbCRCMotCaAFw97CQy2qwM/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/17/year-pictures-part/cbCRCMotCaAFw97CQy2qwM/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 12:13:08 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>2014 Year in Pictures: Part I</title>http:<description>
 -- 
By Thea Breite&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/12/15/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/Thea-Year%20End/779cd44b9a75431cb730aeaeb8139c57-779cd44b9a75431cb730aeaeb8139c57-0.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;A pedestrian struggles to cross a street in blowing and falling snow as the Gateway Arch appears in the distance Sunday, Jan. 5, 2014, in St. Louis. An artic blast of cold winter air affected a good portion of the country for a week. Freezing cold made it all the way to Florida and is blamed for more than 20 deaths nationwide
  (Jeff Roberson/AP)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/15/the-best-photos-part/wDd9frTph2aBLaa4yFRXpJ/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/15/the-best-photos-part/wDd9frTph2aBLaa4yFRXpJ/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 18:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Protesters rally in downtown Boston over police killings</title>http:<description>About 1,000 people demonstrated Saturday in downtown Boston to protest over the recent deaths of Michael Brown in Ferguson, Mo. and Eric Garner in New York City. State Police said they arrested 23 people for disorderly conduct after a skirmish near Nashua Street Jail.
 -- 
By Lloyd Young&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/12/14/BostonGlobe.com/Metro/Images/kesner_protest3_met.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Demonstrators held a sit-in in downtown Boston.
  (Kieran Kesner for The Boston Globe)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/13/protesters-rally-downtown-boston-over-police-killings/0JwpSCBVlTOEVFlnCvuEfP/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/13/protesters-rally-downtown-boston-over-police-killings/0JwpSCBVlTOEVFlnCvuEfP/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 18:10:40 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Powerful storm pounds West Coast</title>http:<description>A strong storm hit the West Coast this week, causing overflow of rivers and flooded freeways. Northern and southern California dealt with power outages, wind damage and landslides.
 -- 
By Leanne Burden Seidel&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/12/12/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/5f26745fd0644ee6a1e25514e94c6799-5f26745fd0644ee6a1e25514e94c6799-0.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;A resident of Guerneville, Calif., who parked his car overnight in the Safeway parking lot in Healdsburg, finds it nearly completely submerged as Foss Creek topped it's banks, Dec. 11.
  (Kent Porter/The Press Democrat via Associated Press)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/12/powerful-storm-pounds-west-coast/ac2ImBj8Ms35fSMLy4MzRP/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/12/powerful-storm-pounds-west-coast/ac2ImBj8Ms35fSMLy4MzRP/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 18:13:54 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>The best photos of 2014: stories behind the Globe’s most memorable pictures of the year</title>http:<description>Each year, editors from the Globe Magazine (www.bostonglobe.com/magazine) and the Boston Globe photo department choose the most memorable and incisive pictures  of the last 12 months from staff photographers.  The 2014 photos that follow -- and the behind-the-scenes stories about them, as told to reporter Elizabeth Gehrman -- will appear in the Globe Magazine on Sunday, December 14. (And scroll down for additional great pictures that we couldn’t fit in the print magazine.)
 -- 
By Francis Storrs&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/11/26/BostonGlobe.com/Magazine/Images/Ryan_giraffe.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;October 15 / Dorchester  -- This photograph of a baby at the Franklin Park Zoo is cute, but also, when people see it, they go “Is that the giraffe’s body or what is it?” Then they read the caption and realize it must be the mother. I try to get the readers’ attention in my pictures. That’s my whole idea of having fun with photography, trying to reach out to the readership and make a picture that will catch their eye.
.


  (David L. Ryan/Globe Staff)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/10/the-best-photos-stories-behind-globe-most-memorable-pictures-year/0NcwF9IhOGPfvlYP14zaBK/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/10/the-best-photos-stories-behind-globe-most-memorable-pictures-year/0NcwF9IhOGPfvlYP14zaBK/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 20:30:51 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Massive fire in downtown Los Angeles</title>http:<description>The huge fire shut down parts of two major freeways early Monday morning.
 -- 
By Thea Breite&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/12/08/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/Thea_fires/2014-12-08T153929Z_1248196751_TM3EAC80TBZ01_RTRMADP_3_USA-CALIFORNIA-FIRE.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Los Angeles city firefighters battle a massive fire at a seven-story downtown apartment complex under construction in Los Angeles, California December 8, 2014. 
  (Gene Blevins/Reuters)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/08/massive-fire-downtown-los-angeles/OG8rGuhTrWFZ1ySAYVMUvI/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/08/massive-fire-downtown-los-angeles/OG8rGuhTrWFZ1ySAYVMUvI/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 20:20:08 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Affordable housing crisis in Brazil</title>http:<description>Affordable housing in Rio de Janeiro is in high demand for the city of twelve million. The city is dealing with a housing crisis daily, with about 220,000 people without a proper place to live. With the Olympics coming in 2016, real estate has become too expensive for many. Recently, several hundred squatters were evicted from a housing complex and forced to live back in the slums.
 -- 
By Leanne Burden Seidel&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/11/29/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/c29c4db6294d4eb3aacd09bd03482787-ee9e95c7188f46d1999e52a955d2dde9-0.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;A boy walks on a dirt road of the Terra Prometida, or Promised Land shantytown, in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil on Nov. 14. An estimated 220,000 Rio de Janeiro residents are trapped by the city's chronic housing deficit. There are simply not enough affordable houses to meet demand in this city of 12 million
  (Leo Correa/Associated Press)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/05/affordable-housing-crisis-brazil/0JWqrm6f0EFddo1vT8k1VK/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/05/affordable-housing-crisis-brazil/0JWqrm6f0EFddo1vT8k1VK/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 23:24:36 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Globe photos of the month, November 2014</title>http:<description>

&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/11/06/BostonGlobe.com/Metro/Images/davis_baker2_met.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Governor-elect Charlie Baker shared a laugh with Billy Farrell during a visit to the Eire Pub in Dorchester.

  (Jim Davis/Globe Staff)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/03/globe-photos-month-november/O6K1GXLvgyzgZiAOf2bRXI/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/03/globe-photos-month-november/O6K1GXLvgyzgZiAOf2bRXI/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 18:07:24 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Hong Kong protesters and police clash</title>http:<description>Pro-democracy protesters tried to surround the government headquarters in the Admiralty district of Hong Kong. After failing to shut down the government, pro-democracy leader Joshua Wong announced that he and two other members of his group will go on a hunger strike until the city’s chief executive restarts dialogue on electoral reform.
 -- 
By Thea Breite&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/12/01/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/tb_hong/Hkg10124615.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Pro-democracy protesters gather at Tamar, near the government headquarters in the Admiralty district of Hong Kong on December 1, 2014.
  (Dale de la Rey/AFP/Getty Images)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/01/hong-kong-protesters-and-police-clash/IrCObFZsJJw1DPGkmkaOKJ/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/12/01/hong-kong-protesters-and-police-clash/IrCObFZsJJw1DPGkmkaOKJ/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 18:16:56 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Strike up the band</title>http:<description>Over the decades, marching bands at Boston’s public high schools slowly died out, a victim of dwindling resources and interest. On Thanksgiving Day, the English High Marching Band band will revive that tradition.
 -- 
By Lloyd Young&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/11/20/BostonGlobe.com/Metro/Images/27bandpics09.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;English High Marching Band tuba player Isiah Fitzgerald-Johnson, 17, of Jamaica Plain joked with Keishawn Guillaume, 16, of Jamaica Plain (right) before the start of band practice in Jamaica Plain.
  (Jessica Rinaldi/Globe Staff)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/26/strike-band/nTKaAWV49wLKacuoHLwbqL/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/26/strike-band/nTKaAWV49wLKacuoHLwbqL/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 22:07:30 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Reaction to the Ferguson decision</title>http:<description>

&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/11/25/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/459550636.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Demonstrators celebrate as a business burns after it was set on fire during rioting following the grand jury announcement in the Michael Brown case on Nov. 24 in Ferguson, Missouri. 
  (Scott Olson/Getty Images)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/24/ferguson-waits-and-reacts/pahWflEa5XUilnFObOhAUK/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/24/ferguson-waits-and-reacts/pahWflEa5XUilnFObOhAUK/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 17:10:59 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Life during the battle of Kobani</title>http:<description>The Syrian town of Kobani has been under attack by Islamic State militants since September. As the Kurdish fighters defend their city, displaced residents are forced to live in camps across the border into Turkey. 
 -- 
By Leanne Burden Seidel&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/11/21/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/5061756a5e304a98adf59e7a3347b5d5-5061756a5e304a98adf59e7a3347b5d5-0.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Jamila, center, sister of 19 year-old Syrian Kurdish fighter girl Perwin Mustafa Dihap who died after being wounded during fighting against the Islamic State forces in her home town of Kobani, cries holding her picture, during the funeral in Suruc, on the Turkey-Syria border, Nov. 7. Kobani, also known as Ayn Arab, and its surrounding areas, has been under assault by extremists of the Islamic State group since mid-September and is being defended by Kurdish fighters. 
  (Vadim Ghirda/Associated Press)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/21/life-during-battle-kobani/Y9PvVg8lXfiyMJ7PtfOahJ/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/21/life-during-battle-kobani/Y9PvVg8lXfiyMJ7PtfOahJ/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 00:21:12 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Snow buries area in upstate New York</title>http:<description>More than 6 feet of lake-effect snow was dumped in the Buffalo, N.Y., area over the last few days with reports of more on the way.  Storms closed a 100-mile plus section of the New York State Thruway, and the US National Guard has been called in to help dig out.
 -- 
By Lloyd Young&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/11/20/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/9a0c028846494e5cb50ea431763264b7-d5ef06fa667e448db2c925c791c4991d-0.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;A man digs out his driveway in Depew, N.Y., on Nov. 19. The Buffalo area found itself buried under as much as 5½ feet of snow Wednesday, with another lake-effect storm expected to bring 2 to 3 more feet by late Thursday.



  (Derek Gee/The Buffalo News via Associated Press)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/19/snow-buries-area-upstate-new-york/qwCeLRqBLm4BKUkEoD5hcM/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/19/snow-buries-area-upstate-new-york/qwCeLRqBLm4BKUkEoD5hcM/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 18:32:16 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Portraits</title>http:<description>A portrait often pauses events and allows viewers to look into the eyes of the participants. Candid moments are usually how stories are told, but sometimes the interaction between photographer and subject tells its own story. Like a movie character who breaks the fourth wall, a portrait can arrest our gaze when we’re otherwise focused on narrative, forcing us to consider an individual. Collected here is a celebration of that special genre of photojournalism, the portrait.
 -- 
By Lane Turner&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/11/16/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/portraits/de9cf747cecc44b988859887079cdc21-fbc7f0fd661743e5a824d3bb9798ce78-0.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;A man watches as Indian Sikhs protest the acquittal of ruling Congress party leader Sajjan Kumar in New Delhi, India, Wednesday, May 8, 2013. 
  (Altaf Qadri/associated press)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/17/portraits/krBKTAS1kCtQui2nRdmU2K/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/17/portraits/krBKTAS1kCtQui2nRdmU2K/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 20:52:41 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>The Natural World: November weather</title>http:<description>November can bring a variety of changes in the weather to many different regions. Among the long shadows of autumn, cold temperatures, winds and snow begin the transition to winter in the northern hemisphere. 
 -- 
By Leanne Burden Seidel&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/11/13/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/Leanne-%20Natural%20November/7ee43e681003459f825b68b6e16ba904-7ee43e681003459f825b68b6e16ba904-0.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Snow melt from a roof forms into icicles in Bozeman, Mont., Nov. 11. 
  (Adrian Sanchez-Gonzalez/Associated Press)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/14/the-natural-world-november-weather/axAkzIlPXm2wmqinMc5yLN/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/14/the-natural-world-november-weather/axAkzIlPXm2wmqinMc5yLN/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 21:12:16 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Veterans Day 2014</title>http:<description>United States veterans who have served in the armed forces were honored during Veterans Day events yesterday. It coincided with other countries marking Armistice Day or Remembrance day (Poppy Day), when in the 11th hour of the 11th day of the 11th month, the armistice between the allied nations and Germany in 1918 effectively ended World War I.
 -- 
By Lloyd Young&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/11/11/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/46ea4b72a71840aa9442afd9b03069b6-ac2f6e6e4c4841198e584e13cc946ab5-0-513.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;US Army Georgia National Guard Staff Sgt. Tracy Smith (right) a veteran of the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, embraces Korean War veteran Jim Conway, 84, as military service members are asked to sing along to the Armed Services Medley during a Veterans Day ceremony at the Atlanta History Center on Nov. 11 in Atlanta.


  (David Goldman/Associated Press)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/12/veterans-day/8WqQFwP42TMe8cNCu0J6EL/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/12/veterans-day/8WqQFwP42TMe8cNCu0J6EL/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 21:34:12 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Monochrome</title>http:<description>Some of the best photographs in color make no attempt to utilize the entire available palette. A splash of just one hue can crystalize a moment or a mood in a way that a full spectrum often cannot. Sometimes black and white photography simplifies a chaotic world, stripping away distractions to focus on the subjects at hand. This isn’t necessarily true all the time, and there are many reasons for creating images in black and white. The monochrome image as well gives photographers that same distillation of intent that black and white can achieve, and still allows for the vibrant saturation of real life. Collected here are images that celebrate the primarily monochrome vision.
 -- 
By Lane Turner&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/11/09/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/monochrome/DV1889554.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;A Yeoman Warder stands amongst the ceramic poppies as Queen Elizabeth II and her husband Prince Philip, Duke of Edinburgh, visit the Tower of London's 'Blood Swept Lands and Seas of Red' poppy installation at the Tower of London on October 16, 2014. The art installation will eventually consist of over 800,000 ceramic poppies, and serves to symbolise British and Colonial military fatalities in WW1.
  (BEN STANSALL)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/10/monochrome/UG8emV0Db8pcz9f7kjrvlK/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/10/monochrome/UG8emV0Db8pcz9f7kjrvlK/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 22:05:08 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Art in public spaces</title>http:<description>Art in public spaces enriches our lives in various ways, in many places. It can send important messages to the community, make people more aware the environment, and let them see it in a different way.  Here is an homage to the artists who create for all to see, and to the photographers who captured it.
 -- 
By Leanne Burden Seidel&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/11/03/BostonGlobe.com/BigPicture/Images/Leanne-%20public%20Art/2014-10-13T155638Z_228491361_BM2EAAD1CLJ01_RTRMADP_3_GERMANY-CULTURE.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;German street artist 'Sokar uno' paints a mural which is part of the Urban Nation art project, on a residential building in Berlin Oct. 13. 
  (Fabrizio Bensch/Reuters)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/07/art-public-spaces/tyJPXcMBgNC8P9eXNCMa2M/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/07/art-public-spaces/tyJPXcMBgNC8P9eXNCMa2M/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 21:21:09 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Globe photos of the month, October 2014 </title>http:<description>The death of former mayor Thomas M. Menino, politicians on the campaign trail, the last day of racing at Suffolk Downs, and more of last month’s best images from the Globe staff.
 -- 
By Lloyd Young&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/10/31/BostonGlobe.com/Metro/Images/Copy%20of%20kreiter_meninodeathcityhall9_met.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;A bouquet of flowers lay on the steps of City Hall in memory of former mayor Thomas M. Menino, who died Oct. 30. 

  (Suzanne Kreiter/Globe staff)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/05/globe-photos-month-october/HF4BfRo5Yc0sLT33kgY3iK/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/05/globe-photos-month-october/HF4BfRo5Yc0sLT33kgY3iK/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 17:16:49 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Election 2014</title>http:<description>

&lt;br /&gt;<![CDATA[<img src=http://c.o0bg.com/rf/image_960w/Boston/2011-2020/2014/11/05/BostonGlobe.com/Metro/Images/05mainbar08.jpg>]]>&lt;br /&gt;Flanked by his wife Lauren (left) and running mate Karyn Polito, Charlie Baker addressed supporters early Wednesday morning at the Seaport Boston Hotel. 

Flanked by his wife Lauren (left) and running mate Karyn Polito, Charlie Baker addressed supporters early Wednesday morning at the Seaport Boston Hotel.
  (Jessica Rinaldi/Globe Staff)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</description>
<link>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/04/election/fRiMKXxm5onViw818csDKP/story.html</link>
<guid>http://www.bostonglobe.com/news/bigpicture/2014/11/04/election/fRiMKXxm5onViw818csDKP/story.html</guid>
<categories/>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 14:18:42 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
